We’re interested in the Absolute Truth.
Siamo interessati nella Verità Assoluta.
There’s Absolute Truth and relative truth.
C'è la Verità Assoluta e la verità relativa.
[Golden Mean of the Infinite]
[Sezione Aurea Dell'Infinito]
Śrila Guru Mahārāj tells us the word ‘sādhu’
Śrila Guru Mahārāj ci dice che la parola "sādhu"
is based upon the word ‘sat’, which means ‘eternal’.
si fonda sulla parola "sat", che significa "eterno".
The sādhus, they’re interested in the eternal world, the permanent world.
I sādhu, sono interessati al mondo eterno, il mondo permanente.
Vadanti tat tattva-vidas tattvaḿ yaj jñānam advayam
Vadanti tat tattva-vidas tattvaḿ yaj jñānam advayam
brahmeti paramātmeti bhagavān iti śabdyate [SB: 1.2.11].
brahmeti paramātmeti bhagavān iti śabdyate (SB: 1.2.11).
This advaya-jnan, this one thing to be known,
Questo advaya-jnan, questa unica cosa da conoscere,
can be understood in terms of three aspects:
può essere compresa secondo tre aspetti:
Brahmā, Paramātmā and Bhagavān.
Brahmā, Paramātmā e Bhagavān.
Brahman, impersonal conceptions,
Brahmin, concezione impersonale,
appear superficially to be able to contain everything.
a prima vista appare essere in grado di contenere tutto.
Paramātmā, at the other extreme, smaller than the smallest.
Paramātmā, all'altro estremo, più piccolo del più piccolo.
So, Guru Mahārāj poses the question in this way,
Allora, Guru Mahārāj pone la questione in questo modo:
“If these are the extremes of the Infinite,
«Se questi sono gli estremi dell'infinito,
and in reference to this question, the extremes of the Absolute,
ed in riferimento a questa questione, gli estremi dell'Assoluto,
what will be the central conception?
quale sarà la concezione centrale?
What is the central conception of the Infinite?”
Qual è la concezione centrale dell'infinito?».
kṛṣṇera yateka khelā, sarvottama nara-līlā, nara-vapu tāhāra svarūpa
Kṛṣṇera yateka khelā, sarvottama nara-līlā, nara-vapu tāhāra svarūpa
gopa-veśa, veṇu-kara, nava-kiśora, naṭa-vara, nara-līlāra haya anurūpa [Cc: 2.21.101]
gopa-veśa, veṇu-kara, nava-kiśora, naṭa-vara, nara-līlāra haya anurūpa (Cc: Madhya, 2.21.101).
The central conception of the Infinite, means ‘the golden mean’,
La concezione centrale dell'infinito, ossia la "sezione aurea" è
is Kṛṣṇa conception,
la concezione di Krishna,
which is distinguished by what?
che si distingue per cosa?
Human-like proportions.
Le fattezze umane.
So it’s easier for people to accommodate
Così è più facile per le persone accettare
the Infinite as being greater than the greatest
l'Infinito come più grande del più grande,
that they can think of,
questo lo possono concepire,
or even smaller than the smallest.
o perfino più piccolo del più piccolo.
But to think of the Infinite,
Ma pensare all'Infinito,
the central conception of the Infinite,
la concezione centrale dell'Infinito,
the aprākṛta-līlā of Kṛṣṇa which is a-prākṛta—
la aprākṛta-līlā di Kṛṣṇa che è aprākṛta,
like mundane, but not.
come il mondano, senza esserlo.
Human-like.
Di fattezze umane.
Human-like dimensions, human-like proportions.
Dimensioni umane, proporzioni umane.
So it’s that Supreme Absolute Truth
Allora è quella la Suprema Verità Assoluta
Brahmā, Paramātmā, and Bhagavān.
Brahmā, Paramātmā e Bhagavān.
But even within Bhagavān there’s gradation.
Ma perfino in Bhagavān c'è una graduazione.
From Lakṣmī–Narāyaṇ, Sītā–Rām, Rukmiṇī–Dvārkadhiś,
Da Lakṣmī–Narāyaṇ, Sītā–Rām, Rukmiṇī–Dvārkadhiś,
and Radhā–Kṛṣṇa and the Vraja-gopis in Vrīndāvan.
e Radhā–Kṛṣṇa e le Vraja-gopi di Vrīndāvan.
Whenever we speak of these things,
Ogni volta che parliamo di queste cose,
there are many levels that they’re to be understood on,
ci sono molti livelli che devono essere compresi,
and it’s like the spiritual version
ed è come la versione spirituale
of the unified fields theory,
della teoria del campo unificato,
that proper siddhānta will help us
che il corretto siddhānta ci aiuterà
understand everything in it’s proper place.
a comprendere ogni cosa nel modo giusto.
But even in the Supreme Absolute Truth there’s gradation.
Ma perfino nella Suprema Verità Assoluta c'è una gradazione.
Yes, that is good, but go further.
Si, va bene, ma andate oltre.
Can you go further?
Potete andare oltre?
Guru Mahārāj’s paraphrase of this is
Guru Mahārāj usa questa parafrasi
“Dive deep into Reality”.
"Immergiti profondamente nella Realtà".